# Ananta Shahane, M.Sc.

☑ ananta.shahane@icloud.com

Ananta Shahane

in Ananta Shahane



# **Objective**

/anantashahane

As a recent Master's graduate in Foundations of Computing from Universiteit Leiden, I bring a profound understanding of Evolutionary Algorithms, essential for navigating complex search spaces in real-world energy challenges. My academic experiences have equipped me with unique problem-solving skills, particularly suited for innovative solutions.

## **Education**

# Universiteit Leiden, The Netherlands

Master of Science—Computer Science

2021-2023

Thesis: A Corridor Model Evolutionary Algorithm, for Fast Converging Green Vehicle Routing Problem Coursework: Quantum Algorithms, Evolutionary & Combinatorial Algorithms, Multimedia Systems, Software Testing & Verification, Robotics, Modern Game AI, Computational Models & Semantics, Deep Learning, Embedded Systems.

#### Pune University, India

Bachelor of Engineering—Computer Engineering

2014-2018

Thesis: A Broker Model for Micro-Service Orchestration

*Coursework*: Object Oriented Programming, Microprocessor Architecture, Operating Systems, Data Structure and Problem Solving, Computer Graphics, Digital Signal Processing.

# **Relevant Experiences**

Fall 2023 Research Thesis @Leiden Institute of Advanced Computer Science, under Prof. Y. Fan

Remodelled *genetic algorithm* for *green vehicle routing problem* accounting for customers' locality, and engineered *corridor model*. Reduced average AUC for 92 benchmarks of 500 iterations by 10%.

Evolutionary Algorithm | Swift | Python | Multi Objective Optimsation | NSGA-II

Fall 2022 Evolutionary Intelligence, Prof. Hao Wang (LIACS)

Designed genetic algorithm for searching DL Architecture for image detection; revealed the link between adjacency matrices and the crossover operator, improving convergence speed and stability.

Python | nasbench | Evolutionary Algorithm | Deep Learning | iOH Analyser

2018-2022 Self Employed: iOS Developer

Developed, published and supported a cross platform app "Today Productivity' on iOS, iPadOS and macOS, designed to assist users plan and execute their days, with widgets and iCloud support.

Xcode | Swift | SwiftUI | RDBMS | CloudKit | WidgetKit | Publishing | Web Development

2017-2018 Trusting Social: Gilmour Proxy

Engineered a robust proxy for the Gilmour micro-service broker system, facilitating universal access across programming languages via HTTPS. It efficiently manages a vast array of micro-services.

Golang | Micro-Services | Docker | Prometheus | Linux | macOS | HTTP Protocol

## Skills

Frameworks

Minecraft(gdmc), json, HTTPS Protocol, SwiftUI, Qt, Cirq, Openfermion, Scikit-learn, Keras.

Languages C++, C, Swift, Python, Golang, Markdown.

### Miscellaneous

2013-2014 Certificate of Merit; Physics (Centre Point School, India)

Awarded for Excellence in Physics by the British Council International School Awards ( $1^{st}/120$ ).

**Fundamentals of Red Hat Enterprise Linux** (edX)

Awarded for 100% completion of course, with 8 assignments, 6 weeks.

Networking and Security in iOS Applications (University of California, Irvine via Coursera)
Awarded for 98% grade of course, spanning 4 months and 16 assignments.

2010 National Cyber Olympiad Scored #1,896 (91 percentile) in National Olympiad.

Conferences Free Open Source Software Meet (2018), try! Swift Banglore (2017), GopherCon 2018, Kernel Meetup 2017-2018, Google Meetup 2018, Quantum Games (2023), Quantum Amsterdam (2023).

Scores ToEFL: 101/120 GRE: 316/340 (Quant: 167, Verbal: 149), Hackerrank: 78% solved.

Activities **Biking** (1800<sup>+</sup> km); **Gaming**: Tekken 7 (Finished 17th of 107 in national DOJO event); **Music**: Jazz; **Hobby**: PC Building, **Trekking** 180km in 5 days to Pindhari Glacier.